Alex Pedersen

Developer & OpsGuy with a passion for creating simple, efficient and scalable solutions.

me@alexpdr.com

github.com/alexpdr

linkedin.com/in/alexpdrs

+31 (0) 622 935 677

Breda, The Netherlands

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer @ EnergyWorx

Dec 2020 - May 31 2021

Feature development on the company platform, adviced on the larger overall migration towards generic/open-source technologies, adviced on infrastructure optimization and needs and developed new python services.

*third-party integrations, platform development, backups, open-source/generic technologies.

Backend Developer @ YoungOnes

Dec 2019 - July 2020

Advisor and architect on the re-design and migration of the company platform into a decentralized (micro)service based environment.

Managed company python infrastructure such as CI/CD pipelines, hosting and backups.

Established and managed documentation, code standard and procedures for application & network security including routines for disaster recovery and incident reporting.

*software architecture, devops, secops, service design and development

Backend Developer @ OfficeApp

Apr 2019 - Nov 2019

Developed python tools & web (micro)services and applications for client integration and internal feature development targeting the company's AWS based platform.

*third-party service integration, multi-threaded sensor based management services.

Software Engineer @ Onpoint Creative Agency

Apr 2019 - Nov 2019

Architected and created python tools, web-services and applications to meet various client and internal development cycle needs.

*scraping, processing, analysis and crypto trading software.

Technologies & tools

OpenAPI, REST, FastAPI, Masonite, Dash, Django, Connexion, Pandas, BS4, Pydantic, OAuth, AsynclO, Pytest(asgi), WebTest, Maria/MySQL, Redis, Rethink, Postgress dbs++

Git(Hub/Lab), Docker, Traefik, Drone CI, Postman, Stoplight++

Industry Knowledge

Python API & service architecture, design, development, deployment and maintenance.

DevOps & infrastructure maintenance, analysis and optimizations

Languages

Norwegian (native) English (fluent) Dutch (basic)

Platforms

DigitalOcean, AWS, GCP

Other

Open-source & self-hosting CyberSec (CTF) hobbyist Competitive Gamer





EDUCATION

Software Development (College)

Fontys University of Applied Sciences 2017 - 2019, Eindhoven, The Netherlands

Computer Engineering (BSc)

University of Agder 2016 - 2017, Grimstad, Norway

ICT-Service & Infrastructure (Trade Diploma)

Nordahl Grieg VGS | Dataoppdrag AS 2012 - 2015, Bergen, Norway

BACKGROUND

Software Dev & Ops

The majority of my professional development work has been in creating new and migrating older legacy systems using open-source tooling and scalable, distributed technologies.

This has meant extensive work with modern, containerized service and serverless technologies paired with DevOps tasks such as CI/CD management, automations, bots, and other developer workflow accelerating optimizations and improvements.

Primary language has been Python for the last 4 1/2 years professionally, and >10 years personally. Secondary language has recently been Rust to fill in specific low-level requirement features.

Software Tester

Before I went on to dedicated development work (and later ops) I breifly worked as a software tester working on the testing, documentation and verification of devices and software for the deployment of the Norwegian smart power grid. This later grew into a love for automation and static analysis tools for with Python.

SysAdmin & ICT

Started as a system administrator and consultant where I worked on deployment, monitoring and administration of and extensive amount of (windows/linux)servers, various third-party and client; CRM, mail(exchange), database, networking, firewall systems.